two chapter 32 of Black Beauty this LibriVox recording is in the public
public domain Black Beauty by Anna Su Part three chapter 32 A Horse
Fair No doubt a horse fair is a very amusing place to those who have nothing
to lose; at any rate, there is plenty to see. Long strings of young horses out of
the country, fresh from the marshes; and droves of shaggy little Welsh ponies, no
higher than merry legs and hundreds of cart horses of all sorts, some of them
with their long tails braided up and tied with scarlet cord; and a good many
like myself, handsome and high Brad but fallen into the middle class, through
some accident or blemish, unsoundness of wind, or some other complaint. There were some splendid
animals quite in their prime, and fit for anything; they were throwing out their
legs and showing off their paces in high style, as they were trotted out with a
leading rain the groom running by the side.
But round in the background there were a number of poor things, sadly broken down
with hard work, with their knees knuckling over and their hind legs
swinging out at every step, and there were some very dejected looking old
horses, with the under lip hanging down and the ears lying back heavily, as if
there were no more pleasure in life, and no more hope; there were some so thin that you
might see all their ribs, and some with old soars on their backs and hips.
These were sad SES for a horse to look upon, who knows not but he may come to
the same state. There was a great deal of bargaining a running up and beating down;
and if a horse may speak his mind so far as he understands, I should say there
were more lies told and more trickery at that horse fair than a clever man could
give an account of. I was put with two or three other
strong useful looking horses, and a good many people came to look at us.
The gentleman always turned away from me when they saw my broken knees; though the
man who had me swore it was only a slip in the
stall. The first thing was to pull my mouth open, then to look at my eyes, then
to feel all the way down my legs, and give me a hard feel of the skin and
flesh, and then try my paces. It was wonderful what a difference
there was in the way these things were done. Some did it in a rough off-hand way,
as if one was only a piece of wood; while others would take their hands gently
over one's body, with a pat now and then, as much as to say, “By your
leave.” Of course I judged a good deal of the buyers by their manners to
myself. There was one man, I thought, if he would buy me, I should be happy. He was
not a gentleman, nor yet one of the loud, flashy sort that call themselves so. He
was rather a small man, but well made, and quick in all his
motions. I knew in a moment by the way he
handled me, that he was used to horses; he spoke gently, and his gray eye had a
kindly chery look in it. It may seem strange to say— —but it is
true all the same— —that the clean, fresh smell there was about him made me take
to him; no smell of old beer and tobacco,
which I hated, but a fresh smell as if he had come out of a hay
loft He offered £23 for me, but that was refused, and he walked away.
I looked after him, but he was gone, and a very hardl looking loud voiced man came.
I was dreadfully afraid he would have me; but he walked off two or three more came
who did not mean business. Then the hard-faced man came back again and offered
£23 A very close bargain was being driven, for my salesman began to think he
should not get all he asked, and must come down; but just then the gayyed man
came back again.
I could not help reaching out my head toward him. He stroked my face
kindly. “Well, old chap,” he said, “I think we should suit each other. I'll give 24 for
him.” “Say 25 and you shall have him 2410 said my friend, in a very
decided tone, “and not another sixpence— —yes or no?” “Done,” said the salesman; “and you may
depend upon on it there's a monstrous deal of quality in that horse, and if you
want him for cab work he's a bargain.” The money was paid on the spot,
and my new master took my halter, and led
me out of the fair to an inn, where he
had a saddle and Bridal ready. He gave me
a good feed of oats and stood by while I ate it, talking to himself and talking to
me. Half an hour after we were on our way to London, through pleasant lanes and
country roads, until we came into the great London thoroughfare, on which we
traveled steadily, till in the twilight we reached the great
city. The gas lamps were already lighted; there were streets to the right, and
streets to the left, and streets crossing each other, for mile upon mile. I thought
we should never come to the end of them.
At last, in passing through one, we came to a long cab stand where my rider
called out in a cheery voice good night governor hello cried a voice. “Have you
got a good one?” “I think so,” replied my owner. “I wish you luck with him.” “Thank you,
governor,” and he rode on. We soon turned up one of the side
streets, and about halfway up that we turned into a very narrow street, with
rather poor looking houses on one side, and what seemed to be coach houses and stables on the
other. My owner pulled up at one of the houses and whistled. The door flew open,
and a young woman, followed by a little girl and boy, ran out. There was a very
lively greeting as my rider dismounted. “Now, then, Harry, my boy, open
the gates, and mother will bring us the lantern.” The next minute they were all
standing around me in a small stable yard Is he gentle, father?” “Yes, Dolly, as
gentle as your own kitten; come and pat him.” At once the little hand was patting
about all over my shoulder without fear.
How good it felt! “Let me get him a brand mesh while
you rub him down,” said the mother. “Do, Polly, it's just what he wants; and I know
you've got a beautiful mash ready for me.” “Sausage dumpling and apple turnover!”
shouted the boy, which set them all laughing. I was led into a comfortable
clean smelling stall, with plenty of dry straw, and after a capital supper I lay
down, thinking I was going to be happy
end of chapter